Simon Verhoeven

simonaverhoeven@gmail.com UK and Swiss National +6583630416

04-15 Suites@Katong 263 Tanjong Katong Rd Singapore, 437050

PROFILE

A keen Software Developer/Consultant with 10 years' experience in IT Professional Services. Driven to learn and dive deep into problems and technologies. Looking for a hands-on role working with technologies that excite me. Interested in full stack development, serverless application architecture, infrastructure as code and frontend technologies.

SKILLS

- Frontend JavaScript/TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, D3.js, Web Components (Stencil), Webpack, CSS, Sass
- Backend Node.js, Java (Spring Boot)
- DevOps Jenkins, GitHub Actions, Docker, AWS Cloud Development Kit, Terraform
- AWS API Gateway, Lambda, Cognito, DynamoDB, EC2, ECS
- Testing Jest, Puppeteer, Cypress, JUnit, Selenium
- Agile Methodologies Scrum methodology, JIRA
- Web and Real-Time Protocols: SOAP, REST, GraphQL, WebSockets
- Relational and NoSQL Databases Postgres, MySQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB
- Fundamental Computing Skills Windows, Mac, Linux/UNIX, Batch/Shell
- Public Speaking Frequent experience in presenting ideas and technologies to large groups

WORK EXPERIENCE

Alpaca Consultants, Singapore

Founder, CEO

July 2022 - Current

- Technology consultant for startups across various sectors, including shipping, logistics, and e-learning.
- Design, architect and build solutions.
- Manage an international team of full stack developers.
- Specialize in AWS, Node.js, React.js, TypeScript, Java (Spring Boot), GraphQL.

Telepathy Labs, Singapore

February 2022 - Current

Senior Software Engineer

- Architect and build several Telepathy Labs software products.
- Technologies: Node.js, React.js, Next.js, TypeScript, Docker, GraphQL.
- Schedule, supervise and delegate tasks among other developers.

Whire (whire.net), Singapore

June 2021 - November 2023

- Chief Technology Officer
 - Set the technical direction for product development.
 - Manage and oversee all IT-related elements of the business.

Zühlke, Singapore

July 2020 - January 2022

Expert Software Developer

- Responsible for developing IT architectures of innovative software solutions and for strategic client technology consulting.
- Technologies: Node.js, React.js, TypeScript, Jenkins, Docker, Java (Spring Boot).
- Frontend Capability Owner: Responsible for reviewing technology horizons (key technology nologies used in current and future projects) and planning learning for developers.
- Conducted initial and final stage interviews.

Appway AG, Zurich / Appway, Singapore

September 2014 - June 2020

- Senior Architect
 - Involved in every step of the product development life cycle from requirements to training.
 - Designed and implemented several large-scale enterprise applications.
 - Influenced key stakeholders by proposing new and alternative solutions.
 - Supported and maintained production environments.

PROJECTS

Stella Platform Portal, Singapore - Admin Portal

- Developed platform for tracking and managing Stella Automotive AI, a digital assistant for car dealerships (handles reception desk and service scheduling lines).
- Technologies: Node.js, Next.js, TypeScript, Jest, Docker, GraphQL, .NET.
- Frontend team lead: Coached team members, delegated tasks, reviewed pull requests.

Standard Chartered Bank, Singapore - Internet Banking Application

- Developed features focusing on customer wealth management.
- Technologies: Node.js, React.js, TypeScript, Jest, Cypress, Puppeteer, Jenkins, Docker, Java (Spring Boot), GraphQL.
- Setup processes/tools for frontend and backend teams to create/edit GraphQL schema and mock responses. Presented a new way of working to key decision makers and provided support throughout its adoption.

Whire (whire.net), Singapore - Web Recruiting Platform

- Designed and implemented entire application architecture.
- Technologies: Node.js, TypeScript, Next.js, GraphQL, AWS Cloud Development Kit, AWS Lambda, ECS, Fargate.

Julius Baer, Singapore - Portfolio Management Application

- Led workshops with the client to outline business and technical requirements.
- Developed a full stack automated portal for assignment, visualization and filtering of employee work items; JavaScript, SQL.

Credit Suisse, Zurich - Customer Account Opening Application

- Heavily involved in sprint planning and story creation (using JIRA).
- Implemented customer document generation, integrated with Silanis Esign.
- Implemented integrations to backend systems: SOAP, REST, Oracle, Apache ActiveMQ.
- Best Practices Coordinator: Led weekly code reviews to ensure high codebase quality.

Credit Suisse Trust, Zurich - Trust Structures Management Application

- Responsible for entire application architecture, from concept to development and Go Live.
- Led project scoping meetings (outlining achievable goals within budget).
- Responsible for client billing.
- Integrated the application with multiple web services (SOAP) in 4 global locations.

EDUCATION

University of York

2011 - 2014

BEng Computer Science with a year in industry (2:1)

Bilborough College

2008 - 2010

A-Levels: Mathematics (A), Physics (A), Computing (B)

TECHNOLOGY INTERESTS

Alpaca Cup (alpacacup.com) - Wakeboard Competition App

- Created a competition management app for event organizers and competitors.
- Serverless web application: AWS Cloud Development Kit, AWS Lambda (Node.js), GraphQL (Apollo), React.js.
- Launched in April 2021, has been used to host 50+ live competitions.

OTHER

Sports

- Wakeboarding, skiing (competed at University level), skydiving, trampolining and cycling.
- Completed a charity bike ride from York to Paris as a team of 5. Raised over £500 for Cancer Research UK.

Foreign Languages

• Confident conversational German (CEFR B2 level).

REFERENCES

Available on request